<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.3.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-01-12T13:01:09-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000//</id><title type="html">So Magnetic</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">What is design strategy? Why we need to opt for a more professional process</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/archive/design-strategy" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What is design strategy? Why we need to opt for a more professional process" /><published>2017-12-26T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2017-12-26T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/archive/design-strategy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/archive/design-strategy">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*5PFeKnwrCgPXdk0J7xHiCg.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-is-design-strategy&quot;&gt;What is design strategy?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-we-need-to-opt-for-a-more-professional-process&quot;&gt;Why we need to opt for a more professional process&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I may continue to add to this document as the year progresses. So keep tabs on
this. If there’s anything you want expanded upon, let me know. 🤓&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This term means a many different things to designers nowadays. What design
strategy sounds like to one might be completely different to the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing to understand about strategy in design is that we are all a part of
it, in both large an small forms, with different roles along the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;but-what-is-strategy-to-designers&quot;&gt;But what is strategy to designers?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve often wondered why this was important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My job as a designer has been to make a graphic that satisfies the request for
the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You want a new logo? Done.&lt;br /&gt; You want your website designed? Here ya go.
Here’s a design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think about a friend that I used to design for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our relationship in the past was that I ask him what he wanted made and then
made that design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There wasn’t any strategy or questionnaire. There wasn’t any focus on value or
improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There wasn’t even any talk of what happens after the design… I just made him a
logo and branded his website, two different times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that was two different designs of the same thing in one year. He eventually
came back to me one last time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why wasn’t the branding sticking? Why did we have to revisit it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I agreed to take on the client again, but this time. &lt;strong&gt;We opted for a more
professional process&lt;/strong&gt;.
(&lt;a href=&quot;http://cmps.co/client-onboard-1&quot;&gt;cmps.co/client-onboard-1&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing is, I’ve known now for the last 10 months that creating a design
agency based on being valuable to the business would require positioning myself
and my brand as a problem solver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hear about it all the time from other designers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;we-need-to-be-practicing-design-strategy&quot;&gt;“We need to be practicing Design Strategy.”&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what is it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;you-hear-these-all-the-time&quot;&gt;You hear these all the time.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;theres-some-mystical-art-called-design-strategy&quot;&gt;There’s some mystical art called design strategy.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;strategy&quot;&gt;Strategy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wasn’t sure where it was practiced the most. Maybe in big business and large
scale design teams?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not very familiar with large scale design teams. But because I eventually
plan on positioning myself around C-level execs doing high budget design, I’ll
have to learn it sooner than later as I get my team together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m currently positioning my design process to uncover value and opportunities
in order to deliver strategic design solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of what I have planned to write about covers this throughout next year.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://compassofdesign.com/&quot;&gt;Our newsletter will have tons of resources on this
too.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The whole idea of strategy may seem like it comes from designers who are paid a
lot of money from big companies. It seems like they’ve somehow “made it” as a
designer, a design firm, or team. They’re the ones getting the really cool
projects to work on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;its-because-theyve-found-a-way-to-bridge-the-gap-from-design-to-business&quot;&gt;It’s because they’ve found a way to bridge the gap from design to business.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You need to find that way of bridging the gap between the business of design and
the design of business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;targets-and-metrics&quot;&gt;Targets and Metrics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Businesses have goals they are shooting for all the time. Even if it’s just to
make it through the month without going under.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some businesses that have a better system of setting and achieving
goals, and some who need a lot of help defining and measuring success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Designers may have access to one but not the other, so in order for us to do our
jobs, we need to know what we are trying to do (beyond creating a new logo or
website design) and how we are going to measure the success of this project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;positioning&quot;&gt;Positioning&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Positioning in the marketplace is key to a project’s success. In order for a
business to position themselves correctly we need to figure out where they exist
now in the market and where they want to go as a result of your project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You start with what the company does, both features and benefits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Figure out the values they use to make decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn about their positioning statement built on why someone should choose them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then your job is to fulfill that through visual design in order to move them
closer to where they want to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sales-and-marketing-funnels&quot;&gt;Sales and Marketing Funnels.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-buyers-journey&quot;&gt;The buyers journey.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Funnels are a fun topic on why someone should choose to go further into the
brand. At some point what you are designing becomes a piece of this funnel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a journey through how someone goes from a non-customer into a brand
ambassador. You will have people spread throughout all sections in your target
market or user personas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understanding what frame of mind someone is at when they get to what you are
designing for will help you figure out how to position that piece to convert
them further down the funnel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;insight&quot;&gt;Insight&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Insight comes from poring over company data that is either supplied or collected
during your research phase of design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This valuable data frames much of how we approach and attack the problem in
order to remember who and what we are designing for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Hint: it’s probably not the CEO that you are designing for. It’s the end user
that has to use, see, or interact with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-does-strategy-matter&quot;&gt;Why does strategy matter?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When you understand what a business or brand is trying to accomplish, you can
propose a solution that answers the business problem with creativity. —&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/2fhVNcX&quot;&gt; Douglas
Davis, Creative Strategy and the Business of Design&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Design strategy is our first defense of being relevant in the industry of both
design and business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Business is transactional.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In order for someone to give up money for a product or service, they need to
value the results more than the money they give up for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this puzzle, the focus is bringing people to the business and delivering
value through products and services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We as designers are a piece of that puzzle that, when put together, deliver the
whole picture on what value is behind the product or service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without trying to learn what a business is trying to accomplish, we might
mis-represent the very thing we are trying to help sell. Regardless of how
interesting the design is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Companies will pay top dollar to get results. And if you don’t deliver on those
results, or if you never figured out what the results should be, your client
will feel like you failed them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The client will then either leave you now, or never come back later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-secret-to-design-strategy&quot;&gt;The secret to design strategy?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Design strategy is actually Business Strategy in disguise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A while back, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/d_evyn/status/915605019512078337&quot;&gt;I had sent out this
tweet&lt;/a&gt;. It was kind of a
revelation because I’ve been reading and studying strategy for designers, only
to learn that design strategy has very little upfront to do with design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more I thought about it, the more this quote from Helen Tran (designer) gave
in August rang through my head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Designers need to add value to business in a manner that helps them move the
needle closer to success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are actual goals a business has when they open for business. They need to
make money, and their form of business provides value of some sorts to their
customers through products and services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason design strategy is so foreign to designers is that the ability to
design is usually held in a different part of the brain than the skills for
running / managing a business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The ability to design is usually a separate skill than the skills necessary to
run and manage a business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fundamentally, creativity and logic sit on opposite sides of the brain.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A designer who spends time giving insights on how you can solve a business
problem with a creative solution will ultimately help you position yourself as
more than a pixel pusher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You essentially earn your seat at the decision table through providing relevant,
creative solutions to difficult problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;its-the-execution-that-sets-you-apart&quot;&gt;It’s the execution that sets you apart&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-do-we-need-to-learn-as-designers&quot;&gt;What do we need to learn as designers?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;were-really-good-at-learning-new-design-skillsbr-how-does-this-translate&quot;&gt;We’re really good at learning new design skills.&lt;br /&gt; How does this translate?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;learn-to-speak-the-language-at-the-table&quot;&gt;Learn to speak the language at the table.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you expect to be included in the high level conversations going on in the
business, especially being able to dictate how something is designed without the
client or management playing “creative director,” you need to become fairly good
at speaking the language of business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need to show them that you understand what the metrics and mechanics working
behind the design are and how your work will impact that. I have really good
resources below on this, but you must learn the lingo before you can tango with
the big bosses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;you-need-to-learn-to-ask-why&quot;&gt;You need to learn to ask “why.”&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By questioning what it is you’re designing for, you’re opening the discussion to
figure out the “who” and “what” we’re designing this in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s the bridge between being tactical (short term) and focusing on strategy
(long term).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;find-out-the-other-goals-at-the-table&quot;&gt;Find out the other goals at the table.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Design is just one step along the journey of creating a product or service. When
Helen talked about having a “Seat at the table” above, we need to find out who
else in at that table and learn what their goals are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve ever done a group project before, each person is tasked with a goal
using their best skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each person needs to have communication to make sure they are completing the
same project in the way that compliments the other departments, and that each is
pulling their weight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same is true with your role as designer(s) in the project. Each department
has certain goals to hit. Usually those departments include but aren’t limited
to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Marketing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Copywriters&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sales&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Production&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Product Engineering&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Developers and IT&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Corporate Offices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a designer, it should be your duty to help facilitate the success of the
project, and the only way is to learn what they are trying to solve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m currently working on learning this through action. Me and my current clients
are using their project as a base for my brand strategy process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://compassofdesign.com/community/?=strategy&quot;&gt;Compass of Design
community&lt;/a&gt; will get regular
updates and developments on this process as they happen&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;for-now-i-can-give-you-some-sources-to-use&quot;&gt;For now, I can give you some sources to use.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;where-to-learn-more-about-strategy&quot;&gt;Where to learn more about strategy.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;keep-your-eyes-peeled-for-good-resources-out-there&quot;&gt;Keep your eyes peeled for good resources out there.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Congrats, you’re now aware of design and it’s role in business. Even if you knew
about it already, these are still insanely helpful resources to learn more about
design strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll be covering topics on design strategy for the next year as I work on
learning it myself and practicing it with clients. Until then…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m going to list resources that I have found to be helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://compassofdesign.com/books&quot;&gt;The Compass of Design Book List&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A list of every book I’ve found to be helpful as a designer, especially on
design strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/2fhVNcX&quot;&gt;Creative Strategy and the business of design.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Specifically this book. This is the best bridge between the language of business
and it’s translation to design.&lt;br /&gt; (afl) This book is important for designers
trying to bridge that gap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/2xkzGbV&quot;&gt;101 things I learned in Business School&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is probably one of the fastest ways to understand the language that is used
in high level business terms. There’s illustrations, explanations and quick
snippets of how these terms apply to business. Though it’s not design centric,
having this knowledge helps you understand what or why a business is talking
about a certain term.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.process.st/checklist/brand-identity-design/&quot;&gt;Brand Identity
Checklist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A thorough list of every thing you should go over in branding a business with
resources and other sources there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because branding is what I do, this was helpful, but there is a lot of crossover
with other industries&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.conversionchecklist.org/&quot;&gt;Conversion Checklist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A look into things marketers are looking for when creating landing pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This&lt;a href=&quot;http://thefutur.libsyn.com/blair-enns&quot;&gt; podcast episode &lt;/a&gt;with the writer of
&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/2xffUgi&quot;&gt;Win Without Pitching Manifesto&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://thefutur.libsyn.com/blair-enns&quot;&gt;http://thefutur.libsyn.com/blair-enns&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;These posts by InkBot Design&lt;br /&gt;  — &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/inkbot-design/what-is-brand-strategy-48d1722822c6&quot;&gt;What is brand
strategy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
— &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/inkbot-design/small-business-marketing-growth-strategies-for-2017-4fb733a42325&quot;&gt;Small Business Marketing Growth
Strategies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
— &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/inkbot-design/marketing-and-advertising-strategies-45242269f5ee&quot;&gt;Marketing and advertising
strategies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
— &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/inkbot-design/brand-development-strategy-tips-6a6a18317b36&quot;&gt;Brand Development
Strategies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pINigXJTpxE&quot;&gt;This video by Hollingsworth&amp;amp; about design and
business&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Any and all of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCzBkNPSxw15qrW_Y8p-oCUw&quot;&gt;High Resolution
Podcasts.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://designbetter.co/design-thinking&quot;&gt;Design Better’s design thinking online
book&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;those-who-i-do-consulting-with-will-also-get-the-best-of-everything-i-know-and&quot;&gt;Those who I do consulting with will also get the best of everything I know and&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;learn this year about positioning your business as a design strategist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until then, enjoy the new year and we’ll pick up with the newsletter again on
the 4th of January. 🤓&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/1*mo7_gcoDhIhJHCOLPxMfLg.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;still-trying-to-fill-the-gap&quot;&gt;Still trying to fill the gap?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Come join other like-minded designers who are working at becoming masters of
their craft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every week we go over ways to market yourself better by improving your design
skills, your personal brand, and other topics to further develop as a great
designer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tap either picture to get started investing in your design skills (:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;figcaption_hack&quot;&gt;Tap on either picture to get started at compassofdesign.com&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://read.compassofdesign.com/tagged/design?source=post&quot;&gt;Design&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://read.compassofdesign.com/tagged/design-thinking?source=post&quot;&gt;Design
Thinking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://read.compassofdesign.com/tagged/business?source=post&quot;&gt;Business&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://read.compassofdesign.com/tagged/business-strategy?source=post&quot;&gt;Business
Strategy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://read.compassofdesign.com/tagged/ux?source=post&quot;&gt;UX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By clapping more or less, you can signal to us which stories really stand out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;darian-rosebrookhttpsreadcompassofdesigncomdarianrosebrook&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://read.compassofdesign.com/@darianrosebrook&quot;&gt;Darian Rosebrook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brand Identity Designer for &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/itssomagnetic&quot;&gt;@itssomagnetic&lt;/a&gt;,
running a design community at
&lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/compassofdesign&quot;&gt;@compassofdesign&lt;/a&gt;. I write to help others
grow their skills as designers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;compass-of-designhttpsreadcompassofdesigncomsourcefootercard&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://read.compassofdesign.com/?source=footer_card&quot;&gt;Compass of Design&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the best design articles written by members of the Compass of Design
Community to help you strengthen your skills in design, business/freelance, and
marketing yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interesting…&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="case-study" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Privacy Policy</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/archive/privacy-policy" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Privacy Policy" /><published>2017-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2017-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/archive/privacy-policy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/archive/privacy-policy">&lt;h1 id=&quot;br&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ONLINE PRIVACY POLICY AGREEMENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Magnetic LLC, (So Magnetic), is committed to keeping any and all personal
information collected of those individuals that visit our website and make use
of our online facilities and services accurate, confidential, secure and
private. Our privacy policy has been designed and created to ensure those
affiliated with So Magnetic LLC of our commitment and realization of our
obligation not only to meet but to exceed most existing privacy standards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THEREFORE&lt;/strong&gt;, this Privacy Policy Agreement shall apply to So Magnetic LLC and
any subsidiary company listed below , and thus it shall govern any and all data
collection and usage thereof. Through the use of
&lt;a href=&quot;https://compassofdesign.com&quot;&gt;https://compassofdesign.com&lt;/a&gt; you are herein
consenting to the following data procedures expressed within this agreement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Subsidiary Company:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compass Of Design&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Darian Rosebrook Designs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Collection of Information&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This website collects various types of information, such as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;· Voluntarily provided information which may include your name, address, email
address, billing and/or credit card information etc., which may be used when you
purchase products and/or services and to deliver the services you have
requested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;· Information automatically collected when visiting our website, which may
include cookies, third party tracking technologies and server logs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please rest assured that this site shall only collect personal information that
you knowingly and willingly provide by way of surveys, completed membership
forms, and emails. It is the intent of this site to use personal information
only for the purpose for which it was requested and any additional uses
specifically provided on this site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We may also gather information about the type of browser you are using, IP
address or type of operating system to assist us in providing and maintaining
superior quality service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is highly recommended and suggested that you review the privacy policies and
statements of any website you choose to use or frequent as a means to better
understand the way in which other websites garner, make use of and share
information collected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use of Information Collected&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Magnetic LLC may collect and may make use of personal information to assist
in the operation of our website and to ensure delivery of the services you need
and request. At times, we may find it necessary to use personally identifiable
information as a means to keep you informed of other possible products and/or
services that may be available to you from
&lt;a href=&quot;https://compassofdesign.com&quot;&gt;https://compassofdesign.com&lt;/a&gt; and our subsidiaries
. So Magnetic LLC and our subsidiaries may also be in contact with you with
regards to completing surveys and/or research questionnaires related to your
opinion of current or potential future services that may be offered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Magnetic LLC does not now, nor will it in the future, sell, rent or lease any
of our customer lists and/or names to any third parties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Magnetic LLC may feel it necessary, from time to time, to make contact with
you on behalf of other external business partners with regards to a potential
new offer which may be of interest to you. If you consent or show interest in
presented offers, then, at that time, specific identifiable information, such as
name, email address and/or telephone number, may be shared with the third party.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Magnetic LLC may deem it necessary to follow websites and/or pages that our
users may frequent in an effort to gleam what types of services and/or products
may be the most popular to customers or the general public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Magnetic LLC may disclose your personal information, without prior notice to
you, only if required to do so in accordance with applicable laws and/or in a
good faith belief that such action is deemed necessary or is required in an
effort to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;· Remain in conformance with any decrees, laws and/or statutes or in an effort
to comply with any process which may be served upon So Magnetic LLC and/or our
website;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;· Maintain, safeguard and/or preserve all the rights and/or property of So
Magnetic LLC; and&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;· Perform under demanding conditions in an effort to safeguard the personal
safety of users of &lt;a href=&quot;https://compassofdesign.com&quot;&gt;https://compassofdesign.com&lt;/a&gt;
and/or the general public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Children Under Age of 13&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Magnetic LLC does not knowingly collect personal identifiable information
from children under the age of thirteen (13) without verifiable parental
consent. If it is determined that such information has been inadvertently
collected on anyone under the age of thirteen (13), we shall immediately take
the necessary steps to ensure that such information is deleted from our system’s
database. Anyone under the age of thirteen (13) must seek and obtain parent or
guardian permission to use this website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unsubscribe or Opt-Out&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All users and/or visitors to our website have the option to discontinue
receiving communication from us and/or reserve the right to discontinue
receiving communications by way of email or newsletters. To discontinue or
unsubscribe to our website please send an email that you wish to unsubscribe to
hello@compassofdesign.com. If you wish to unsubscribe or opt-out from any third
party websites, you must go to that specific website to unsubscribe and/or
opt-out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Links to Other Web Sites&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our website does contain links to affiliate and other websites. So Magnetic LLC
does not claim nor accept responsibility for any privacy policies, practices
and/or procedures of other such websites. Therefore, we encourage all users and
visitors to be aware when they leave our website and to read the privacy
statements of each and every website that collects personally identifiable
information. The aforementioned Privacy Policy Agreement applies only and solely
to the information collected by our website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Magnetic LLC shall endeavor and shall take every precaution to maintain
adequate physical, procedural and technical security with respect to our offices
and information storage facilities so as to prevent any loss, misuse,
unauthorized access, disclosure or modification of the user’s personal
information under our control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The company also uses Secure Socket Layer (SSL) for authentication and private
communications in an effort to build users’ trust and confidence in the internet
and website use by providing simple and secure access and communication of
credit card and personal information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes to Privacy Policy Agreement&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Magnetic LLC reserves the right to update and/or change the terms of our
privacy policy, and as such we will post those change to our website homepage at
&lt;a href=&quot;https://compassofdesign.com,&quot;&gt;https://compassofdesign.com,&lt;/a&gt; so that our users
and/or visitors are always aware of the type of information we collect, how it
will be used, and under what circumstances, if any, we may disclose such
information. If at any point in time So Magnetic LLC decides to make use of any
personally identifiable information on file, in a manner vastly different from
that which was stated when this information was initially collected, the user or
users shall be promptly notified by email. Users at that time shall have the
option as to whether or not to permit the use of their information in this
separate manner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Acceptance of Terms&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through the use of this website, you are hereby accepting the terms and
conditions stipulated within the aforementioned Privacy Policy Agreement. If you
are not in agreement with our terms and conditions, then you should refrain from
further use of our sites. In addition, your continued use of our website
following the posting of any updates or changes to our terms and conditions
shall mean that you are in agreement and acceptance of such changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to Contact Us&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or concerns regarding the Privacy Policy Agreement
related to our website, please feel free to contact us at the following email,
telephone number or mailing address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Email:&lt;/strong&gt; 4256225706&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mailing Address:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Magnetic LLC&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1107 South 3rd Street&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mount Vernon, Washington 98273&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;05/02/2017&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>
